<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biranjan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Biranjan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Twitter Bot with R</title>
      <link>/2017/10/making-twitter-bot-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/making-twitter-bot-with-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was just playing with Twitter API so that I could automatically like Tweets from certain twitter account like for example work. And then I realized
you can do quite more than just like the tweet. You can re-tweet the tweet, follow people, send messages and lot more.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about datatable in R</title>
      <link>/2017/09/let-s-talka-about-datatable-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/let-s-talka-about-datatable-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Tables Tables are the inevitable part of every data scientist or analyst job. There will always be a situation where data can be best communicated by simply displaying them in rectangular boxes. In those situation I resort to a smart and versatile datatable from DT package.
library(DT) datatable(head(mtcars))  Okay if you think it comes with too may bells and whistle then her’s a way to tune it down. And also by default datatable show 10 entries even though there is no 10 entries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to take your predictive model to next Level using Shiny</title>
      <link>/2017/08/how-to-take-your-predictive-model-to-next-level-using-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/how-to-take-your-predictive-model-to-next-level-using-shiny/</guid>
      <description>Building a predictive model must be one of the usual task for students to do in their machine learning or predictive modelling class.However, when I was student I often had lingering question what to do with model now ? In this post I will talk about how to take your predictive model to the next level and make a web app where other people can interact with your model. The final outcome will look like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I made my personal finance dashboard</title>
      <link>/2017/07/creating-your-personal-finance-dashboard-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/creating-your-personal-finance-dashboard-in-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once in a while I like to know how am I doing with my expenses but my bank doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any application where I can break down my expenses.

However, my bank does provide a financial statement albeit in a not so helpful .txt format.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive time-series plots in R</title>
      <link>/2017/07/interactive-time-series-plots-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/interactive-time-series-plots-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Plotting Time Series Object There are lots of good plotting packages in R. And in this post I would like to show some of the interactive charting libraries to plot time series in R. If the object that you are trying to plot is a time-series object then one can plot it really easily.
 lungDeaths &amp;lt;- cbind(mdeaths, fdeaths) str(lungDeaths) ## Time-Series [1:72, 1:2] from 1974 to 1980: 2134 1863 1877 1877 1492 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo and blogdown in GitHub</title>
      <link>/2017/07/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I wanted to start a blog in git-hub first I thought Jekyll was the only option. Although Jekyll is natively supported by git-hub however it is not the only static site that git-hub can handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>